FOO JIA QUAN

Final Year Student at Temasek Poly

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/foo-jia-quan-907525227/ Email: jiaquan81516@gmail.com

Profile

As a goal-driven and curious student, I am passionate in Software Engineering and development thus I want to build up more experience with internships and other opportunities to sharpen my current skills and even upskill myself with new knowledge. One of my goals is to make use of my skills and help the community. My hobbies are cycling, exercising, hiking and learning new technologies.

Skills

- Python
- HTML5/CSS/JS
- Data Analytics
- · Ability to work in a team
- Communication Skills
- Soldering & Circuit Patching

Education

Apr 2020 - Mar 2023 Temasek Polytechnic

Diploma in Electronics

-TP LEADership PROGRAMME(TPLEAD):

- Workshops, seminars, and networking to understand better about global issues we are facing(eg. sustainability) and come up with some strategies on how we can improve them.
- PRESIDENT of FITNESS CLUB:
- Organize sports events (eg. Powerlifting Meet) and collaborate with other CCAs to spread knowledge on sports & nutrition through seminars.

Apr 2018 - Apr 2020 Education

Higher Nitec in Electronics

Institute of Technical 3.8 GPA (Graduated with Certificate of Merit) -NYAA & Sparrow Club

Jun 2021 - Sep 2021 DHL

Nov 2019 - Feb 2020

Singapore

Logistic Assistant

- · Versatile with different roles.
- Task oriented when instructions were given.

Leapfrog PTE LTD Singapore

Intern

- Testing electronic products and check for defects.
- Input data in company's Excel sheet for further analysis.
- Basic repair with soldering.
- Handle customer relations.

Work **Experience**

Jun 2019

Rohde & Schwarz Memmingen, Germany

Overseas Industrial Attachment

- Exposure to RF semiconductors and wireless communications sector.
- Telecommunications and micro-soldering for PCB manufacturing.

Sep 2018 - Jun 2019 Casio Singapore

Sales Assistant

• ensure that customers get the information they want and clear their doubts about the product.

Certifications	2022	Data Science with Python Simplilearn
	2022	TikTok Youth Camp (Front-end Dev) Bytedance
Awards	2022	Director's List (Temasek Poly)
	2021	Edusave Merit Award (Temasek Poly)
	2021	Business Venture Hackathon (runner up)
	2020	Top Graduate Award (ITE)
	2018 - 2020	Director's List (ITE)

Additional Activities

	2022 June - Present	People's Association (PA) • Part of the PA network, understand the community better and organize community events together with the team.
	2022 Mar - Present	Youth Corps Singapore (YCS)Telecommunications and micro-soldering for PCB manufacturing.
Volunteer Work	2021 Oct - 2021 Dec	Temasek Polytechnic (TP)Conducted introductory Python and Electronics lessons to secondary school students.
	2021 Jun - 2021 Jun	 IMDA Singapore Help cleared the doubts of elderlies with their electronic devices and gave them tips on cybersecurity.
	2019 Mar - 2019 Mar	 nEbO Singapore Spent a day with migrant workers at Tuas dormitory. Went around school to collect meaningful notes written by students for the workers.
Competitions/ Hackathons	2019 Mar - 2019 Mar	Temasek Poly Business Venture Competition (2nd Place out of 18 teams) • Came up with a business plan and formulated LOW-GI Brownies to promote healthy living and came in second place for the competition.